{"name": "63F  2006-6", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to 3x + 6y + 9z ?", "choices": {"A": "3(x + 2y + 3z) ", "B": "3(x + 2y + 9z)", "C": "3(x + 6y + 9z)", "D": "3(x + 2y) + 3z", "E": "18(x + y + z)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. When written in symbols, \"The square of the sum of x and y\" is represented as:", "choices": {"A": "(x2 + y2)2", "B": "x2 + y2", "C": "x2 + y", "D": "x + y2", "E": "(x + y)2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. The odometer in DaNae's car read 18,790 miles when she left on a trip and 19,168 miles when she returned. DaNae drove the car for 7 hours on the trip. Based on the odometer readings, what was her average driving speed on the trip, to the nearest mile per hour?", "choices": {"A": "68", "B": "65", "C": "55", "D": "54", "E": "40"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. The interior dimensions of a rectangular aquarium are 3 feet by 2 feet by 2 feet. What is the volume, in cubic feet, of the interior of the aquarium?", "choices": {"A": "7", "B": "12", "C": "24", "D": "32", "E": "36"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. If a is a real number and 4a = 64, then 2 \u00d7 2a = ? ", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "8", "C": "16", "D": "32", "E": "64"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. For the students enrolled at Sunnyside College, the ratio of male students to female students is 5:7. Which of the following statements about the students enrolled is (are) true?    I.    For every 7 females, there are 5 males.    II.   There are more males than females.    III.  Males comprise  of the students enrolled.", "choices": {"A": "\ud835\udda8 only", "B": "\u2161 only", "C": "\u2162 only", "D": "\u2161 and \u2162 only", "E": "I, \u2161, and \u2162"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. Camille needs  yards of fabric for a craft project. She has  yards of fabric. How many more yards does she need?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. As shown below, the diagonals of rectangle ABCD intersect  at the point (2, 5) in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane. Point A is at (-1, 3). Which of the following are the coordinates of C ?", "choices": {"A": "(-1, 7)", "B": "", "C": "(3, 7)", "D": "(5, 3)", "E": "(5, 7)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": "70m", "B": "11m", "C": "7m + 10", "D": "m + 70", "E": "m + 10"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. The expression 7kl - 3k(4k + 2l) is equivalent to: ", "choices": {"A": "kl - 12k2", "B": "2kl - 7k", "C": "8kl -12k2", "D": "-11kl", "E": "-k2"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. On a recent test, some questions were worth 2 points each and the rest were worth 3 points each. Tuan answered correctly the same number of 2-point questions as 3-point questions and earned a score of 60 points. How many 3-point questions did he answer correctly ?", "choices": {"A": "36", "B": "30", "C": "20", "D": "12", "E": "10"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12.  A postage stamp measures 2 centimeters by 2.5 centimeters. Angelina estimates that the area is 4 square centimeters. Her estimate is what percent less than the actual area? ", "choices": {"A": "80%", "B": "50%", "C": "40%", "D": "25%", "E": "20%"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. The geometric mean of 2 positive numbers is the square root of the product of the 2 numbers. What is the geometric mean of 12 and 48 ?", "choices": {"A": "24", "B": "30", "C": "36", "D": "288", "E": "576"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. A model for the braking distance, d feet, required to stop a certain car when it is traveling x mile\u0219 per hour is . According to this model, what is the braking distance, in feet, required to stop this car when it is traveling 70 miles per hour?", "choices": {"A": "13", "B": "25", "C": "70", "D": "123", "E": "245"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. The expression x2 - x - 30 can be written as the product of 2 binomials with integer coefficients. One of the binomials is (x - 6). Which of the following is the other binomial ?", "choices": {"A": "x2 - 5", "B": "x2 + 5", "C": "x - 5", "D": "x + 5", "E": "x + 6"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. The cost for a company to produce x televisions in 1 year is $150x + $250,000. How many televisions can the company produce in 1 year at a cost of $550,000 ?", "choices": {"A": "1,500", "B": "1,666", "C": "2,000", "D": "3,666", "E": "5,333"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. Given , what is  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "1", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. Teri has $6 less than does her sister, Jennie, who has x dollars. Teri does not spend any money and earns $4. Which of the following is an expression for the amount of money, in dollars, Teri has?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "x + 2", "C": " x + 10", "D": "2x - 2", "E": "x - 2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. A rectangle is 3 times as long as it is wide. The perimeter of the rectangle is 160 meters. What is the area of the rectangle, in square meters?", "choices": {"A": "400", "B": "1,200", "C": "1,600", "D": "3,600", "E": "6,400"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. In the figure below, B is on AE, D is on AG, F is on EG, C is on both AF and BD, \u2220BAC \u2245 \u2220CAD, and\u2220BCF \u2245 \u2220CFG. Which of the following statements must be true?\uff08Note: The symbol \u2245 means \"is congruent to.\") .", "choices": {"A": "EF \u2245 FG", "B": "\u2220ACD \u2245 \u2220CDG", "C": "BD is similar to EG", "D": " \u25b3ABC is the similar to \u25b3ACD", "E": " The areas of quadrilaterals BCFE and CDGF are equal. "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. which of the following is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "-1 \u2716\ufe0f 105"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. Admission to the school fair is $5, and each ride is the same price as any other ride. The graph below shows the total cost for a person, for admission and rides, as a function of the number of rides paid for. One of the following is the price of a single ride. Which one is it?", "choices": {"A": " $1", "B": "$2", "C": "$3", "D": "$4", "E": "$5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. The figure below shows a right triangle whose hypotenuse is 20 inches long. How many inches long is the longer leg of this triangle?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "40", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. If you add up 6 consecutive even integers that are each greater than 25, what is the smallest possible sum?", "choices": {"A": "210", "B": "186", "C": "174", "D": "165", "E": "150"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. As shown below, an 18-foot ramp forms an angle of 12\u00b0 with the ground, which is horizontal. Which of the following is an expression for the vertical rise, in feet, of the ramp?", "choices": {"A": "18 sin 12\u00b0", "B": "18 cos 12\u00b0", "C": "18 tan 12\u00b0", "D": "18 cot 12\u00b0", "E": "18 sec 12\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. If , then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "-33", "B": "-11", "C": "", "D": "11", "E": "33"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. On the way to a family camping weekend, the Estradas stopped at a roadside stand to purchase firewood. The stand sold bundles of pine firewood for $2 per bundle and bundles of hickory firewood for $4 per bundle. The Estradas purchased a total of 25 bundles of pine firewood and hickory firewood for $66. How many bundles of pine firewood did the Estradas purchase?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "11", "C": "17", "D": "21", "E": "22"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. In \u0394ADE below, B lies on AE; C lies on AD; and r, s, t, and v are angle measures, in degrees. The measure of \u2220A is 40\u00b0.  What is r + s + t + v ?", "choices": {"A": "100\u00b0", "B": "140\u00b0", "C": "240\u00b0", "D": "280\u00b0", "E": "320\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Triangles \u25b3ABC and \u25b3DBC, shown below, are isosceles with base BC. Segments BD and CD bisect \u2220ABC and \u2220ACB, respectively. Which of the following angle congruences is necessarily true?", "choices": {"A": "\u2220ABC \u2245 \u2220ACD", "B": "\u2220ABD \u2245 \u2220ACB", "C": "\u2220ABD \u2245 \u2220BCD", "D": "\u2220ACD \u2245 \u2220BAC", "E": "\u2220BCD \u2245 \u2220BAC"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. What is the area, in square feet, of a trapezoid with a height of 4 feet and parallel bases of 7 feet and 5 feet, respectively?", "choices": {"A": "16", "B": "24", "C": "", "D": "48", "E": "55"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. The table below lists the number (to the nearest 1,000) of Boy Scout units (packs, troops, posts, and groups) in the United States for 1994 through 1997. Of the following expressions with x representing the number of years after 1994, which best models the number of Boy Scout units (in thousands) in the United States?Table adapted from U.S. Census Bureau, Statistical Abstract of the United States: 1998. 1998.", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "129x + 1,994", "D": "139x + 1,997", "E": "1994x +129"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.The table below shows the percents of U.S. households with cable television out of all U.S. households with TVs, for each year from 1977 through 1997.Table adapted form The World Almanac and Book of Facts 1999. \u24b81998 by World Almanac Books.32. Which of the following years had the greatest increase in the percent of U.S. households with cable television over the previous year ?", "choices": {"A": "1981", "B": "1982", "C": "1983", "D": "1989", "E": "1990"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.The table below shows the percents of U.S. households with cable television out of all U.S. households with TVs, for each year from 1977 through 1997.Table adapted form The World Almanac and Book of Facts 1999. \u24b81998 by World Almanac Books.33. The figure below shows: a scatterplot for the data points in the table and 5 solid-line: graphs that represent possible models for this data set. Among the 5 lines, which appears to be the best model for the data set ?", "choices": {"A": "A", "B": " B", "C": "C", "D": "D", "E": "E"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Use the following information to answer questions 32-34.The table below shows the percents of U.S. households with cable television out of all U.S. households with TVs, for each year from 1977 through 1997.Table adapted form The World Almanac and Book of Facts 1999. \u24b81998 by World Almanac Books.34. The almanac states there were 64,654,160 U.S. households with cable television in 1996. According to this information, approximately how many U.S. households had TVs, with or without cable, in 1996 ?", "choices": {"A": " 32,000", "B": " 43,000,000", "C": " 97,000,000", "D": " 110,000,000", "E": " 4,300,000,000"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. For all nonzero b and c, = ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "10", "C": "107", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. The function f(x) = x3 - 5x2 + 9x - 5 and line t are shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. Which of the following is an equation of line t, which passes through(3, 4) and is tangent to f(x) at (1, 0) ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": "y = 3x + 4", "D": "y = 2x + 1", "E": "y = 2x - 2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Which of the following degree measures is equivalent to 3.75\u03c0 radians ?", "choices": {"A": "225\u00b0", "B": "337.5\u00b0", "C": "675\u00b0", "D": "1,350\u00b0", "E": "2,700\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Use the following  information to answer  questions  38-40. Hasan and Parvani have a flower bed that is shaped like a  right triangle, as shown below.38. A  bag  of fertilizer  costs  $7.99  and  will  cover  approximately 500 square  feet. Which of the following  is  closest to  the cost, in  dollars, of fertilizing  the  flowerbed?", "choices": {"A": " $25.00", "B": "$95.00", "C": "$110.00", "D": "$150.00", "E": "$190.00"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. Use the following information to answer questions 38-40.Hasan and Parvani have a flower bed that is shaped like a right triangle, as shown below.39. To determine how much fencing to buy to enclose  their  flower  bed,  Hasan  and Parvani  calculated the flower  bed's perimeter. What is its  perimeter, in feet ?", "choices": {"A": "230", "B": "310", "C": "380", "D": "400", "E": "460"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Use the following information to answer questions 38-40.Hasan and Parvani have a flower bed that is shaped like a right triangle, as shown below.40. The angle opposite the 80-foot side measures about 28.1\u00b0. Hasan and Parvani are considering changing the shape of their flower bed. It will still be a right triangle with the 150-foot side as 1 leg, but they will extend the 80-foot side until the angle opposite that side is about 40\u00b0. By about how many feet would they need to extend the 80-foot side ?(Note: sin 40\u00b0 \u2248 0.64, cos40\u00b0 \u2248 0.77, tan40\u00b0 \u2248 0.84)", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "16", "C": "36", "D": "46", "E": "51"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Rectangle ABCD consists of 3 congruent rectangles as shown in the figure below. Which of the following is the ratio of the length of AB to the length of BC ?", "choices": {"A": "1:1", "B": "2:1", "C": "2:3", "D": "3:1", "E": "3:2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Melinda's test average after 6 tests was 73. Her score on the 7th test was 87. If all 7 tests were equally weighted, which of the following is closest to her test average after 7 tests?", "choices": {"A": "87", "B": "85", "C": "80", "D": "75", "E": "73"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. A ball is thrown upward toward a vertical brick wall. The ball hits the wall and bounces back down to the ground. Among the following graphs, which one best represents the relationship between the height, in meters, of the ball and the time, in seconds, from when the ball is thrown until it hits the ground ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. The sides of a right triangle measure 20 cm, 21 cm, and 29 cm. What is the tangent of the angle opposite the side that measures 20 cm?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. The noncommon rays of 2 adjacent angles form a straight angle. The measure of one angle is 3 times the measure of the other angle. What is the measure of the larger angle?", "choices": {"A": "45\u00b0", "B": "60\u00b0", "C": "90\u00b0", "D": "135\u00b0", "E": "145\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. A cube consisting of 8 smaller cubes that are identical is positioned in the standard(x, y, z) coordinate system, as shown below. Vertex A has coordinates (2,0,0), and 3 other vertices are at the origin, on the positive y-axis, and on the positive z-axis, respectively. What are the coordinates of vertex B ?", "choices": {"A": " (0,0,2)", "B": "(0,2,0)", "C": "(0,2,2)", "D": "(2,0,2)", "E": " (2,2,2)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. what is the median of the data given below ?17,  25,  18,  15,  20,  27,  28,  18", "choices": {"A": "17.5", "B": "18", "C": "19", "D": "20", "E": "21.5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. let x \u2295 y = (x - y)3 for all integers x and y. Which of the following is the value of 3 \u2295 (-2) ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "19", "C": "35", "D": "125", "E": "216"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. For all positive integers n, which of the following is a correct ordering of the terms nn, (n!)n, and (n!)n! ?(note: n! =(n)(n-1)(n-2)\u2026(2)(1))", "choices": {"A": "nn \u2265 (n!)n \u2265 (n!)n!", "B": "(n!)n \u2265 nn \u2265 (n!)n!", "C": "(n!)n \u2265  (n!)n! \u2265 nn ", "D": "(n!)n! \u2265 (n!)n \u2265 nn", "E": "(n!)n!  \u2265 nn \u2265 (n!)n"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. What is the perimeter of quadrilateral ABCD if it has vertices with (x, y) coordinates A(0,0), B(1,3), C(4,4), D(3,1) ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "40", "E": "100"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. The graph of the line with equation 3x - 4y = 24 does NOT have points in what quadrant(s) of the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below?", "choices": {"A": " Quadrant I only", "B": "Quadrant \u2161 only", "C": "Quadrant \u2162 only", "D": "Quadrant \u2163 only", "E": "Quadrant I and \u2161only"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. The figure below shows representations of the first 5 triangular numbers, T1 through T5. what is the value of T32 ?", "choices": {"A": "96", "B": "496", "C": "528", "D": "960", "E": "1,056"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. Four distinct points are chosen at random on a circle. Line segments are then drawn connecting every possible pair of these points. These line segments divide the interior of the circle into how many individual, nonoverlapping regions of nonzero area?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "4", "C": "6", "D": "8", "E": "24"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. The radius of a circle is  inches. How many inches \u03c0long is its circumference ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "20", "D": "40", "E": " 80"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. In the (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the radius of the circle having the points (0,-2) and (-6,6) as endpoints of a diameter ? ", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "10", "C": "14", "D": " 25", "E": "100"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. The graph of the function  is shown in the standard(x, y) coordinate plane below. Which of the following, if any, is a list of each of the vertical asymptotes of f(x) ?", "choices": {"A": "x = 0", "B": "x = -1 and x =-2", "C": " y = x + 3", "D": "y = 3x + 2", "E": "This function has no vertical asymptote. "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. The sum of 2 positive prime numbers is a prime number, and 3 times that sum is an odd number. Which of the following prime numbers must be one of the original prime numbers ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "5", "D": "7", "E": "11"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. The set of points created by the midpoints of all chords of length 4 centimeters in a circle of radius 8 centimeters is a :  ", "choices": {"A": "point.", "B": "line segment.", "C": "line.", "D": "semicircle.", "E": "circle."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. If h(x) = f(x) - g(x), where f(x) = 5x2 + 15x - 25 and g(x) = 5x2 - 6x - 11, then h(x) is always divisible by which of the following ?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "5", "C": "7", "D": "9", "E": "17"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. A square, S1, has a perimeter of 40 inches. The vertices of a second square, S2 are the midpoints of the sides of S1, The vertices of a third square, S3, are the midpoints of the sides of S2, Assume the process continues indefinitely, with the vertices of Sk+1 being the midpoints of the sides of Sk for every positive integer k. What is the sum of the areas, in square inches, of  S1, S2, S3, \u2026?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "20", "C": "70", "D": "", "E": "200"}, "correct": "E"}]}